# Ella Madgwick

## **CONTACTS**

#### Email:

madgwickella@gmail.com

Phone: +44 (0) 7902191594

#### LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ella-madgwick-525a78145

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Queenstown Ambassador -2018
- Sports personality of year award (Lancing College) – 2016
- Top 10 retail Sales rep in Vodafone NZ – 2019
- 1st Sports Team, Netball, Tennis, Hockey, Biathlon, Swimming – 2016
- Sales Level 3 2019

#### **SKILLS**

- Mentoring/Coaching Staff
- Customer Service
- Sales
- Interpersonal Skills
- Management
- Leadership

### **PROFILE**

Born and raised in New Zealand, in a small beach town called Whangamata, in the Coromandel Peninsula. Studied in Brighton (UK) for my high school/College education and completed GCSEs/A levels. Decided to move to the adventure capital of the world; Queenstown, New Zealand to study Adventure Tourism Management and graduated with a diploma in 2018.

Worked in the telecommunication and sales industry for over 4 years, for Vodafone New Zealand; worked in many roles within the industry. The most rewarding part about my time at Vodafone was coaching and mentoring my team.

My manager Son Taylor taught me that to be a great coach you must adapt yourself and your approach to every student you have. It is true that there is not one size or style that fits all, you will get different characters/personalities, and some will test you. However, those who test you the most will teach you the most.

In July 2021 I moved back to the UK to complete my citizenship and develop my career further. When I first arrived, I planned to travel around Europe. I completed a cycling tour across France in October 2021. I completed over 1700km/1056miles and cycled to at 62 towns/cities in France. After, my cycle trip I started my hiking tour to one of the most breath-taking places in the world for its mountain range, Switzerland. I travel to around 18 locations in the Swiss alps; I discovered all the hidden gems from the locals I stayed with during my trip.

This year I just completed the Tour Du Mont Blanc, which is located around Italy, France, and Switzerland; The hike was approximately 190km and 10,300 elevation in total. I camped the whole way with my 13kg backpack and meet so many people along the way from all ends of the world. Discovered how beautiful that part of the world, I would highly recommend the hike.

Sports is my first love, whether it is swimming, netball, hockey, etc. I am a huge sports person, and I am constantly motivating people to get outdoors to play sports and enjoy fitness.

# **EDUCATION**

Diploma in Adventure Tourism Management, 2016 - 2018 - Queenstown, NZ

- Financial Planning & analysis
- Operations Management
- Tourism Marketing
- Managerial Accounting
- Cross culture

- Technology in tourism (Photoshop, Microsoft)
- Tourism Management (risks and operations)
- Organisational Behaviour & Human Resource
- Business Development & strategy
  - Commercial Law

High School/College Graduate, 2016 (Lancing College – United Kingdom)

AS/A2 Art - A,B

BTEC Sport Level 3 - Distinction

GCSEs - Religious Studies (A); German (A); Maths (B), Double Science (BB), PE (A); Art (B); English (C) Sports Leadership Level 2 – Distinction

NPLQ Lifesaving Certificate - RLSS, UK (2014) (expired)
First Aid Certificate - Workplace First Aid (2017)

PHEC (Pre-Hospital Emergency Care) - Workplace First Aid (2017)

Education in Marine Biology - Operation Wallacea, Cuba (2015)

**PADI Open water Diving certificate** – 2015

Powerboat level 2 - 2023

Level 1 Swim Teaching Assistant - 2022

Level 2 Swim Teaching - 2022

NVBLQ - Beach Lifeguard - 2023 (valid)

Level 2 Fitness Instructor - 2022

**Level 3 Personal Training – 2022** 

NPLQ – Pool Lifeguard – 2023 (Valid since July)

National Rescue Award for Swimming Teachers and Coaches - 2023

## **WORK HISTORY**

#### Assistant Multi-Site Manager - Vodafone NZ, Queenstown (March 2018 - June 2021)

- Identified and resolved process issues to encourage smoother procedures, more efficient workflow, and overall business growth.
- Mentored employees in reaching objectives aligned with company core values. Managed new employee orientation training process for more than 15 employees.
- Managed inventory control; cash control; Coordinating and mentoring sales personnel to promote workplace morale and productivity.
- Building strong rapport with customers by understanding needs, clearly explaining products and customer escalations.
- Worked in many roles within the company; management; sales representative; service manager;
   Call centre (billing, tech support, sales, provisioning).

# Boat Host and Guide - Southern Discoveries (January 2017 - January 2018)

- Reconciled cash drawer at start and end of each shift, accounting for errors and resolving discrepancies.
- Answered questions, pointed out important features, and offered further details about special exhibits to educate visitors.
- Shared knowledge of menu items and flavours, enabling customers to make personal decisions based on taste and interest.

#### Swimming Teacher – Queenstown Lake District Council (June 2016 – February 2018)

- Provide explanations and demonstrate swimming techniques
- Correct faults in swimming techniques and identify ways to improve performance
- To be a positive role model, creating a positive and fun environment in which to motivate and encourage children and adults to participate in swimming

# Client Engagement Consultant - Estio (February 2022 - August 2022)

- Sell a range of different range of IT and digital apprenticeship courses to organisations to reduce the skills gaps within organisations.
- Using a range of different software including voyager, Microsoft teams, excel, outlook, LinkedIn, etc.
- B2B and B2C Sales, Account Retention, Lead Generation, Lead Conversion, Customer Support, Client Relations, etc.

#### Swim Teacher (June 2022 - Present)

- Teaching Children from stage 1 to 8; from Swim England standards.
- Swim teacher at Leeds City council
- Private lessons in Harrogate Harrogate school of swimming, Neptunes, The swim team

# Adventure Swim Guide - SwimTrek (April 2023 - Present)

- Open water coaching techniques.
- Boat handling skills
- Beach lifeguarding

## **Gaurav Kapoor - Previous Vodafone Manager 2019-2020**

Email: Gauravkapoor10@aol.com

Phone: +64 21 733 117

#### Stephen Aughney - Vodafone Manager present

Email: Stephen.aughney@vodafoneretail.co.nz

Phone: +64 21644002

#### Son Taylor - Vodafone Manager 2011-2020

Phone: +64 21 393 399